

# Gregory Hoffnagle, PMP, MS Tech Mgmt.

Snr. PM, Program/PMO & Portfolio Management (IT)

Atlanta, GA

uplease contact by email

in linkedin/in/gregoryhoffnagle/

visualcv.com/gregory-hoffnagle

### **CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING**

PMP®: Project Management Professional Certification (PMI)

PPMC®: Program & Portfolio Management Certification (PMLG)

CSM®: Certified Scrum Master (Scrum Alliance)

### Six Sigma® Black Belt Training

(SixSigma.us) complete by SEP 2017

**CCNP®**: Former Cisco Certified Networking Professional (Cisco Systems)

MS Project Advanced Training & Risk Management Training

Agile/Scrum Training

Lockheed Martin "Mastering the Future" week long leadership training (division representative)

### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Science in Electronics** Engineering

Capitol Technical University

### Master of Science in Technology Management

University of Maryland, University College

### **MILITARY SERVICE**

### US Army, 2nd Armored Division

### Signals Intelligence Analyst

Formerly held a Top Secret clearance with Special Background Investigation (SBI)

### AWARDS AND MEMBERSHIPS

Lockheed Martin "Top Flight Award"

Lockheed Martin Project Award (PACSES)

Sacramento PMI Member/Volunteer on Membership Committee

Atlanta PMI Chapter Member

### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Senior Program/PMO/Portfolio Manager and former US Army Veteran with a demonstrated history of successfully delivering value in the IT management consulting industry. Skilled in PM framework design (customization to the organization) & adoption, business process, analytical skills, strategic alignment, IT strategy, and business transformation. Strong business management professional with a Master of Science (M.S.) focused in Technology Management from University of Maryland, University College.

### **SKILLS**

Program/PMO/Portfolio Mgmt. IT Infrastructure & Software RFP/Procurements

Program Perf./Dashboards/KPIs

Vendor Oversight / Mgmt. Team Building / Leadership Business Process Management MS Project Expert/Resource Planning

Governance Full SDLC Management PM Mentoring Contract Management

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### 2016 - current **Program Manager, Owner**

ChiCor Consulting, Inc. to Travail, Inc.

### Atlanta, GA Travail Company Startup and Ongoing PM Management

- Provide ongoing Project Management Office (PMO) and project methodology/framework for use by company consultants on various accounts
- Provide small business consulting and advisement to Travail Owner
- Provide dashboard reporting for the portfolio of projects Provide PM mentoring

### 2013 - 2016 **Program Manager**

GVH Partners to PA Dept. of Parks and Recreation (DPR)

### Sacramento, CA - Kronos Human Resource Management Project, \$12MM

- Managed vendor activities and contract deliverables in relation to Kronos SOW including custom DPR hiring modifications
- Managed roadmap for multi-year & multi-phased implementation of DPR HRM
- Managed all PM activities including risk, issues, action items, benefits register, and scope documents
- Conducted Steering Committee monthly presentations with all levels of the Department and Agency Information Officer

## Sacramento, CA - Recreation and Reservation Sales Service (R2S2) Program,

- Led team initiation, development and award of a comprehensive 700 page RFP and Scope of Work (SOW) for a vendor provided application, network, data management, and hardware system, including state park based payment processing devices
- Presented full walk-through of RFP at Bidders Conference including all technical aspects RFP award
- Conducted Steering Committee monthly presentations with all levels of the Department and Agency Information Officer
- Recruited a certified Cost Model Consultant to develop comprehensive RFP cost • Developed stakeholder analysis, benefits management, strategic alignment, and
- governance frameworks Managed RFP team and all PM activities including risk, issues, action items, benefits

### Sacramento, CA - Public Safety Technology Modernization (PSTM) Project, \$16MM

- Engaged with multiple agencies including CA Highway Patrol and CA Department of Fish & Wildlife Wardens
- Met regularly with State Management/Executive teams
- Reviewed vendor PM contract deliverables using SharePoint prior to State review and approval

### 2010 - 2013 PMO Manager and Schedule Team Lead

register, and scope documents

Visionary Integration Professionals (VIP) to CA Franchise Tax Board Sacramento, CA - Enterprise Data to Revenue (EDR) Project, \$522MM

- Led State PMO team in concert with vendor in development of PMO processes and a comprehensive schedule management methodology for a Project Server based 25,000+ task schedule to support custom application development
- Worked with State EDR Management/Executive team (sole contractor at weekly State EDR Manager meetings)
- Reviewed requirements, design, development, testing, training, & implementation activities (full SDLC)
- Reviewed vendor PM contract deliverables prior to approval

### 2008 - 2010 Enterprise Program Management Office (PMO) Manager

Comsys to Hewlett Packard to CA Dept. of Motor Vehicles

### Sacramento, CA - Information Technology Modernization (ITM) Project \$208MM

- Led initial build-out of large enterprise PMO including integration with DMV PMO to manage the development of a custom application on a multi-tiered architecture
- Led PMO team of five HP PMs and five PMO analysts responsible for delivery of HP's design, development, test and implementation of the \$208M ITM system (four major work streams)
- Managed Fixed Price contract, tracking all contract deliverables from compilation to State approval including all application development and COTs/MOTs integration related deliverables
- Managed the creation, maintenance and analysis of all project metrics, reports, KPIs/dashboards, and forecasting
- Provided oversight and guidance for multiple five MS Project schedules (with a master project schedule) containing all HP work
- Provided Organizational Change Management (OCM) utilizing ADKAR framework

### 2008 - 2009 Senior Project Manager

XL Network Group to Active Outdoors to CA Department of Fish & Wildlife

### Nashville, TN - Automated Data Licensing System (ALDS) Project \$23MM

 Revised approximately 15 formal project management and development based plans contract deliverables for the ALDS Project for Active Outdoors (hired as consultant after moving to DMV PMO position)

### 2006 - 2008 Program Manager

Active Outdoors to CA Dept. of Fish & Wildlife (DFW)

### Nashville, TN - Automated Data Licensing System (ALDS) Project \$23MM

- Worked with PM in Nashville, TN (vendor location) to deliver a California statewide deployment of a custom automated fish and game licensing software and COTS touch screen terminal to 1600 point of sale locations statewide (both commercial retailers and state offices)
- Utilized Agile/SCRUM development process for custom statewide application on a multi-tiered architecture
- Managed customer relations and end user adoption and served as adviser to vendor project manager. Developed excellent customer relations as trusted adviser for both Active Outdoors and DFW management/staff
- Authored suite of PM and Software Development/Test related contract deliverables
- Project was awarded technology project of the year by State OCIO office

### 2002 - 2004 Senior Project Manager

XL Network Group, Inc. to PA Integrated Justice Dept.

### Harrisburg, PA - Integrated Justice Enhancement Project \$5MM

- Led team for the State of PA Integrated Justice Network (JNET) providing infrastructure support for JNET including LAN/WAN interfaces to Pennsylvania State Police and local law enforcement offices
- Proposed and led implementation of shared LAN/WAN services with PA Department
  of State to realize significant cost savings of shared infrastructure while adhering to
  customized Service Level Agreements
- Led OCM activities for Infrastructure and User Interface/Experience changes

### 1997 - 2002 PA Infrastructure Director

Lockheed Martin Space Operations LMSO to State of PA Dept of Public Welfare

### Harrisburg, PA - Child Support Enforcement System (PACSES) Project - \$105MM

- Managed all aspects of PACSES Infrastructure involving Federal, State and county government offices
- Managed design and deployment of all project statewide COTS infrastructure and several custom web development projects for the enterprise consisting of 200+ servers, 2200 desktops, T-1 WANs to 67 counties, functional mainframe disaster recovery in Chicago, IL
- On Site Manager leading team of 30 team members including full budget responsibility as well responsible for performance reviews and promotions, merit increases and all HR related matters
- Fully responsible for successful contract management resulting in several contract renewals for upgrade/support

- Lead contractor representative for IRS audit of PACSES project. Authored compliance paper to correct technical areas of concern. Resulted in very positive response from IRS auditor for openness and thoroughness
- Managed Risks and Risk mitigation as well as Issue tracking and closure related to Infrastructure
- Provided leadership and vision for Infrastructure team which included many technology enhancements such as SecureID remote access through a firewall, new web based software development projects and a statewide distributed video training platform to quickly train employees on incremental application enhancements
- PACSES was nationally recognized for successful implementation especially for "The Big Eight States". Project was often referenced as a model system by the Federal Office for Child Support Enforcement (OCSE)

### 1990 - 1996 Lead NASA Project Engineer

Lockheed Martin Space Operations to Computer Science Corporation to NASA

### Seabrook, MD NASA Shuttle Communications (NASCOM) Contract \$75MM

- Planned and implemented an upgraded multiplexer/de-multiplexer (MDM) Space Shuttle Communication System at all major NASA sites in the U.S. Coordinated and performed installation of the mission-critical (Hubble Space Telescope) and humanflight systems (Space Shuttle)
- Sole author of NASA RFP for Data Block Emulator (DBE) testing equipment for use at all major NASA sites in continental U.S. Flown to Florida for successful vendor product acceptance tests
- Regularly attended PM and SDLC meetings including tracking of scope, risks and issue management
- Adopted and worked within Total Quality Management (TQM) framework which was implemented agency wide
- Awarded superior task ratings by NASA task monitors that yielded additional
  contract monies based upon cost-plus award contract structure. Several of the tasks
  had historically been graded "average". Provided superior customer support and
  relationship management